Hey English learners, welcome to this A2
English listening practice video. I hope
you're doing well and that you're ready
to practice your listening. Today I want
to talk about what makes a good English
learner. And of course, this is for any
language, not just an English learner,
but uh a good French learner, a good
Spanish learner. uh what makes a good
language learner. So I want to talk
about four things that make a good
English learner. There are many more
things but I want to highlight four. And
uh before we continue on, if you can
understand me in this video and it's
pretty easy for you to understand what
I'm saying, but you can't understand
native speakers when they speak fast,
then my listening training is for you.
So, make sure you sign up for my
membership and you'll get access to my
listening practice seminars in which I
help you understand native speakers when
they speak fast. So, at the time of
recording this, it's only $2 a month to
sign up. It's cheap, affordable. You
should do that. The link is down below.
Uh, do that so you can improve your
listening. So let's talk about some
different things that make a good
English learner or language learner in
general. So number one, an interest in
other cultures. Okay? When you're
interested in other cultures,
this gives you a reason. This gives you
motivation
to learn the language that you're
learning. Even if it's challenging, even
if you're having trouble, uh it's
difficult for you, you hit a plateau
perhaps.
Regardless of these things, if you have
a real interest, a genuine interest in
other cultures and specifically the
culture that speaks the language that
you're learning, in your case, English.
So perhaps it's American culture,
Canadian culture, Australian culture,
British culture, whatever. If you have
that intense interest in that culture,
it gives you a reason. And having a
reason to learn a language is super
powerful. This makes all the difference.
Okay? When you have a reason, you
actually uh want to do it. You don't
just have to learn the language, but you
want to. That's super uh helpful and
motivating. Uh and it makes it easier I
think. uh it makes you have less
resistance
uh when you encounter differences when
you see that uh the language that you're
learning uh English for example has
these linguistic differences
that you don't quite understand
for a lot of people that can make it
hard for them to continue on with their
language learning. But if you're
interested in other cultures, the
culture that speaks the language that
you're learning,
you are more likely to accept these
differences. These differences aren't
necessarily a problem. You're actually
kind of interested in the differences
just like you're interested in the
different culture. So that helps a lot.
It helped me a lot when I was learning
Spanish. At that time, I was super
interested in Latin America, in Mexico
in particular. I was super excited about
discovering that culture, getting to
know the different aspects of life and
culture and it helped me uh accept the
differences that I was encountering uh
with the Spanish language. So uh that
was uh something that really helped me.
It really aided me in my language
learning. And for example, if you're
looking to become more interested in US
culture, if you want to learn more and
um get excited about learning about the
different states and cities in the US, I
encourage you to check out my US
Conversations podcast in which I talk to
different English teachers from around
the country about their state, their
city. It's a lot of fun. So, that link
is down below. Next, uh the thing I also
the next thing I wanted to mention was
that patience really helps someone be a
better language learner. Okay? You
shouldn't be discouraged about how long
it takes.
Learning a language takes a long time.
Let's be honest, okay? We should be
realistic about our expectations.
we shouldn't expect to become fluent
quickly because that's just simply not
the case. Okay? Uh it's important to uh
understand this and to be patient with
yourself and to be patient during this
process. Uh don't force things. Don't
try to force it to go super super fast.
Of course, try to uh do as much as you
can so that you can learn more quickly
in general. Obviously, you can do that,
but don't force it. Don't get too
anxious about needing to speak really
quickly or needing to understand
everything really quickly. Be patient,
right? If you put in the work and you're
regular with it, it will come. Okay? So,
don't force it. Be patient with
yourself. Uh you're going to make the
same mistakes again and again and again,
hundreds of times in some cases. Okay?
Uh that actually happens. Sometimes it
literally takes like 200 times before
you finally say it right. Okay? Most of
the time you can probably uh learn
things more quickly than that. But
sometimes you make the same mistake many
times, dozens of times. Okay? And you
forget things. All right? Uh we forget
things that we learned in the past. And
so you're going to make the same
mistakes again and again. You're going
to forget things that you learned. So,
you need to be patient with yourself. Be
patient during this process. People
often give up too soon because they're
not patient, right? They just assume
that because it's not easy for them,
because it's taking a while. This means
that they are not talented at language
learning. It's just not for them, right?
uh they come to this conclusion but in
reality they're just not patient. Right?
I've been learning languages for years.
It's a slow process in most cases unless
you are just forced to learn really
quickly for some reason. Sometimes that
happens but most of the time that
doesn't. You have time. you don't need
to learn in two months or else uh your
life is over. That's usually not the
case and because of that it takes a
while. Okay. So, uh a good language
learner is patient during the language
learning process and they're patient
with themselves. Okay. Next, a good
language learner has humility. They are
humble. So, what does this mean? They're
willing to be like a small child, okay?
They're willing to be like a little kid
who's just learning something for the
first time because you're going to get
corrected. You're going to say things
that quite honestly sound funny or
sometimes even ridiculous. Okay? I don't
mean that in a bad way. We all go
through that as language learners. We
say ridiculous things and it's funny.
There's nothing wrong with that. Okay.
Uh I have young children. My son says
some pretty funny, sometimes ridiculous
things and it's funny and we laugh at it
and he laughs at it. He doesn't get all
offended that we're laughing at
something silly that he said wrong or
whatever. We laugh at it and we make it
a positive experience. My son thinks
it's hilarious when he accidentally says
the wrong word, for example. And that's
how we need to be as language learners.
Okay? We need to uh laugh at ourselves,
be humble, not expect to be uh really
good and um expect to be able to say
everything we want to say naturally from
the beginning. It doesn't work like
that. We need to humble ourselves and
understand that we need help. We need to
get corrected. We need to ask other
people for help perhaps when we're
learning a language. We need to not take
ourselves too seriously. And like I
said, we need to laugh at our mistakes.
Okay? If you can't laugh at your
mistakes, language learning is not going
to be fun. Okay? It's going to be pretty
stressful. And when language learning is
stressful, it's often not effective. uh
you often don't progress the way you
would like to progress. So laugh at
yourself. Be like a small child except
that uh you uh are not at the level as
other people or as native speakers.
Okay, all of that is important. All
right, humility. Lastly, a good language
learner is willing to challenge
themselves. Okay? They need to be able
to use content that is actually
challenging for them. Okay? Content
that's a little above your level, that
contains things that are hard to
understand perhaps. Uh and you do this
so that you can reach that level. It's
like going to the gym. If you always
lift the same amount of weight because
it's comfortable for you, then you're
not going to get stronger and lift
heavier weight. You have to put more
weight on the bar or whatever and try
that even though it's challenging in
order to become accustomed to that new
weight. The same thing goes for language
learning. Okay, you need to challenge
yourself and uh use content that's a
little bit harder than what you're
comfortable with and that will get you
accustomed to content at that level.
Okay. Uh, a really practical example of
this is that many people just use my
normal podcast episodes or perhaps they
use uh my YouTube videos in which I
speak slowly and they refuse to start
listening to more advanced content. they
refuse to listen to my advanced
episodes, for example, or they just put
that off and say, "I'll I'll do that
later. I'll do that next year." Right?
And they don't do what they should be
doing, which is challenge challenging
themselves to actually um get accustomed
to what fast English sounds like. Okay?
If that's your case, if you're
comfortable with uh the way I'm talking
now, if you're comfortable with my
podcast episodes and you just want to
stay here,
that's going to cause your improvement
to um go slowly. Okay? It's going to
cause you to um not progress as quickly
as you would like to. uh you have to
challenge yourself. Okay? So for
example, if like I said, if this content
is easy for you, start using more
advanced content. Use my advanced
episodes or use other content that is
more challenging, right? And then of
course uh you need to eventually start
to listen to more than one person
talking, right? That's what I always
talk about when I talk about my US
Conversations podcast. Uh that gives you
the opportunity to listen to two people
talking and not just one. It helps you
become accustomed to uh that type of
situation where there's more than one
person talking. And even just these
videos, I title them A1 or A2. Of
course, I say things and I use language
in these videos that is a little bit
more challenging than A1 or A2. But
that's the point. The point of an A2
video, an A2 listening practice video,
is to help you reach a higher level.
Right? If you're at an A2 level, you
should be listening to content that's
higher than that level, a little bit
higher, so that you can become
accustomed to that higher level content
and reach that level. So, we're at the
end of the video. You know what you need
to do, right? you either need to uh
develop more an in more of an interest
in the culture of whatever uh language
you're learning in your case English. Uh
you need to be patient, okay? Be humble
and challenge yourself, okay? Use
content that's a little challenging for
you so you can reach that next level.
Okay? So, if you want that challenging
content, check out the links down below
uh for my advanced episodes in my US
Conversations podcast. Check those out.
Those will be helpful for you. All
right. Thank you all for watching this
video and I'll talk to you in the next